NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Office File, 1939-1968 (Box 1-37)
  - Davis, John W.
    - Non-legal research, 1953 (Box 10)
    - North Carolina Teachers Association, 1955-1963
    - *Palmetto Education Association (S.C.), 1954-1957
    - Reservations, 1955-1958
    - Southern University, Baton Rouge, La., 1955
    - Speaking requests, 1958-1962
    - Speeches, 1959-1962
    - Teacher Information and Security Department
      - * 1954 Nov.-1955 May
      - * 1955 June-1955 Dec.
      - * 1956
      - 1957
      - 1958
      - 1959
      - * 1960 (Box 11)
      - 1961
      - 1962
      - 1963
      - 1965
        - 1 of 2
        - 2 of 2
      - 1966
  - DeMille, Arnold (Box 12)
    - 1953-1955
    - 1956-1957
  - Dudley, Edward R., 1945-1949, undated
  - File lists, 1951-1952
  - Finances
    - Bequests, 1955
    - Budgets, 1950-1955
    - *Contributions, 1951-1952
    - Field Foundation
      - Annual reports, 1952-1955
      - *Correspondence, 1955-1958
    - Ford Foundation, grant application, 1951-1953
      - 1 of 3
      - *2 of 3
      - *3 of 3
    - Fund-raising
      - Consent forms, 1954, 1963
      - *Correspondence, 1955-1958, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Robert Marshall Civil Liberties Trust, 1955-1957
    - *Seitz, Howard, 1952-1954
    - Theater benefits
      - 1955, "Witness for the Prosecution"
      - 1958, "Oh Captain"
    - Trial balance ledger, 1959-1968
  - Fund Against Intolerance and Racism, Inc., undated
  - Greenberg, Jack
    - Activity reports, 1954-1958
    - *Committee on Relationship with NAACP, 1961-1962, undated
    - Correspondence
      - * 1952-1954
      - 1955-1962
    - Correspondence log, 1951
    - Korea combat case log, 1950-1951
    - Lawyers' conference, 1957
    - Research material, miscellaneous, 1956-1958 (Box 14)
    - Southwest regional conference, 1955
    - Speaking engagements, 1955-1956
    - Writings, 1956, undated
  - *Hall, Carsie, 1956-1957
  - Harvey, Ruth, 1964
  - International Business Machines, 1955-1960
  - Konvitz, Milton
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1944-1946
    - Writings, 1943-1951
  - Law books
    - 1950-1952
    - 1956-1959
    - 1960
    - 1961-1962
  - Law journals and publications
    - Correspondence, 1949-1954
    - Printed material, 1949-1953
  - Laws, Clarence A., 1956-1959
  - Lease agreements, 1952-1956
  - Legal conferences (Box 15)
    - 1946-1947, Federal Power to Protect Civil Rights, Howard University, Washington, D.C.
    - 1949, New York, N.Y.
    - 1951, Washington, D.C.
    - 1953
      - Boston, Mass.
      - School segregation cases, New York, N.Y.
    - 1954, Labor clinic, Waco, Tex.
    - 1955, Atlantic City, N.J.
    - 1958, Dallas, Tex.
    - 1958, New York, N.Y.
    - 1959, New York, N.Y.
    - 1960, Howard University, Washington, D.C.
  - *Legal staff applications, 1945-1963, (4 folders)
  - Legal surveys
    - 1949, 1954
    - 1955, undated
  - Legal workshop handouts (Box 16)
    - Criminal cases, 1950-1953
    - Education cases, 1954-1955
    - Housing cases, 1949
  - *Madison, Waite, 1956-1958
  - Mail sheets, 1952
  - Marshall, Thurgood
    - Article for Common Ground, 1948
    - Awards, 1954-1958
    - Biographical sketch, 1952
    - Congratulatory letters, Brown v. Board of Education, 1954
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
      - 1945, 1950
      - 1951
      - 1952, Jan.-July
      - 1952, Aug.-Dec.
      - 1953
      - 1954, Jan.-Mar.
      - 1954, June-Dec.
      - 1955-1959
    - Correspondence log, 1961
    - Executive Committee, 1950 (Box 18)
    - Expenses, 1952, undated
    - G. I. Assistance Committee, 1950-1951
    - Honorary luncheon, Hotel Delmonico, New York, N.Y., 1951
    - Itineraries, 1950-1952, undated
    - Korean trip See also Container 43, Korean War; Container 99, Korea, defense fund; Containers 152-154, Korea; Container 225, Korean War and World War II Court Martial Records
      - *Case notes, 1951
      - Correspondence, 1951
      - Travel authorization and orders, 1951
    - Masons, 1954
    - Memoranda, 1948-1954
      - 1948
      - 1950-1954
    - Monthly reports, 1954
    - NAACP constitution and bylaws, 1939-1956
    - NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., 1952-1954
    - Press coverage
      - Clippings, 1946-1960
      - Collier's feature article, 1952
      - Releases, 1950-1955
      - Statements, 1951-1956
      - Time cover story, 1955
    - Speaking engagements (Box 19)
      - Events
        - 1951, "Report from Korea," Oakland, Calif.
        - 1952
          - Conference on Research in Race Relations, University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill.
          - Conference on the Courts and Racial Integration in Education, Howard University, Washington, D.C.
          - Harvard Law School Forum, Cambridge, Mass.
          - Institute of Race Relations, Fisk University, Nashville, Tenn.
          - Missouri Assn. for Social Welfare, St. Charles, Mo.
        - 1953, Roosevelt Day Dinner, Americans for Democratic Action, Washington, D.C.
        - 1954
          - American Jewish Congress, New York, N.Y.
          - Atlanta Branch Membership drive, NAACP, Atlanta, Ga.
          - Brotherhood Meeting, Boston, Mass.
          - Brotherhood Week, Middletown, Ohio
          - Herald Tribune Forum, New York, N.Y.
          - New Bethel Baptist Church, Winston-Salem, N.C.
          - North Carolina Conference, NAACP
          - Virginia Conference, NAACP
          - "Youth Wants to Know," Washington, D.C.
        - 1955
          - California engagements
          - Desegregation conference, American Orthopsychiatric Association, Chicago, Ill.
          - John Marshall Conference, Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
        - 1956, White House Conference on Education, Washington, D.C.
      - Requests (Box 20)
        - Denied due to appointment as federal judge, 1961
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1950-1951
          - 1952, Jan.-Mar.
          - 1952, Apr.-June
          - 1952, July-Dec.
          - 1953, Jan.-Mar.
          - 1953, Apr.
          - 1953, May-June
          - 1953, July-Sept.
          - 1953, Oct.-Dec.
          - 1954, Jan.-Feb. (Box 21)
          - 1954, March
          - 1954, Apr.
          - 1954, May
          - 1954, June
          - 1954, July-Aug.
          - 1954, Sept.
          - 1954, Oct.
          - 1954, Nov.-Dec.
          - 1955, Jan.-Mar. (Box 22)
          - 1955, Apr.-June See also Oversize
          - 1955, July-Oct.
          - 1955, Nov.-Dec.
          - 1956, Jan.
          - 1956, Feb.
          - 1956, Mar.
          - 1956, Apr.
          - 1956, May
          - 1956, June
          - 1956, July-Dec.
          - 1957 (Box 23)
          - 1958, Jan.
          - 1958, Feb.
          - 1958, Mar.
          - 1958, Apr.
          - 1958, May-June
          - 1958, July-Aug.
          - 1958, Sept.
          - 1958, Oct.
          - 1958, Nov.-Dec.
          - 1959, Jan.-Feb.
          - 1959, Mar.-Apr.
          - 1959, May-Jnne (Box 24)
          - 1959, July-Sept.
          - 1959, Oct.-Dec.
          - 1960, Jan.-Feb.
          - 1960, Mar.
          - 1960, Apr.-June
          - 1960, July-Sept.
          - 1960, Oct.-Dec.
          - 1961, Jan.-Feb.
          - 1961, Mar.-May
          - 1961, June-Dec.
    - Speeches (Box 25)
      - Background material, 1952-1955, undated
      - Texts
        - 1952, June-1955, May
        - 1955, June-1956, May, undated
    - Testimonial dinner, Baltimore, Md., 1952-1953
    - White, Walter, 1954-1955
    - Wilkins, Roy, 1954-1955
  - McDaniel, Vernon (Arkansas)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955
    - Printed material, 1952-1954
    - Reports
      - 1954
      - 1955
  - Miscellany (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953
    - Inter-office memoranda, 1949-1953
    - Printed material, 1952-1953
    - Statements to the press, 1950-1954
  - *Mitchell, Clarence, 1948-1954
  - Moore, Ming, & Leighton, 1954-1955
  - Motley, Constance Baker
    - Correspondence, 1951-1958
    - Correspondence log, 1951
    - "NAACP and the Supreme Court, 1915-1954," undated
    - Speaking engagements
      - 1952-1954
      - 1955
      - 1956-1957
    - Speeches, undated
  - NAACP (Box 27)
    - Annual conventions
      - 1953, St. Louis, Mo.
        - General
        - Lawyers' conference
        - Resolutions
      - 1954, Dallas, Tex.
        - General
        - Lawyers' conference
        - Resolutions
    - Branches
      - Agent registration, 1958
      - Correspondence
        - 1950-1952
        - 1953
        - 1954-1955
      - Relation to national office, 1953-1954
      - "Special Report of Chairman of Legal Redress Committee to Executive Committee, Chicago Branch, NAACP," 1961
    - Constitution, 1945 (Box 28)
    - Detroit, Mich., branch, 1951-1954
    - Emergency Conference on Integration, Philadelphia, Pa., 1954
    - Great Neck branch, Long Island, N.Y., 1953-1954
    - NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, relation to, 1953
    - Nominating Committee, 1954
    - Pamphlet on segregation, 1953
    - Southeast Regional Office
      - Hurley, Ruby, 1951-1955
      - Reports and press releases, 1952-1955
    - Southwest Regional Office
      - Clippings, 1948-1952
      - Correspondence
        - *Arkansas, 1952-1953
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1948-1952
          - 1954-1960
      - Expenses, U. Simpson Tate, 1956-1968
      - Reports (Box 29)
        - Annual, 1949-1953
        - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954
        - Monthly
          - 1948-1953
          - 1954-1957
    - West Coast Regional Office
      - Organization and conference manual, 1953
      - Reports
        - 1951-1952
        - 1953
        - 1954
      - Williams, Franklin H., 1950-1954
  - National Association for the Advancement of White People, and related organizations, 1954-1955 (Box 30)
  - National Legal Committee, 1953
  - Peyser, Annette
    - 1945-1949
    - 1950-1952
  - Photographs, undated
  - Pinsky, David, 1952-1954
  - Program and objectives, circa 1953
  - Ransom, Leon, 1954
  - *Receipts, 1961
  - Reeves, Frank, 1949-1959 See also Container 146, same heading
  - Reports
    - Annual
      - 1946-1951
      - 1952-1953
    - Board of Directors, 1951
    - Monthly (Box 31)
      - 1946
      - 1948
      - 1949
      - 1951
      - 1952
      - 1953
      - 1954
      - 1955
      - 1956-1959
    - Notes on cases, undated
    - Progress, 1959
    - Staff conferences, 1947-1950
    - Supplement of monthly docket report, 1961
  - Requisitions, 1951-1956 (Box 32)
  - Robinson, Spottswood W.
    - "Brown v. Board of Education, Alternate Memorandum As To Question Five," 1952
    - Correspondence
      - 1946-1949
      - 1950-1954
      - 1955-1961
    - "Memorandum: Techniques in the Handling of School Facilities Cases at the Elementary and High School Level," 1949
    - Reports
      - 1951
      - 1952
  - Schroeter, Leonard, 1951-1953
  - Shagaloff, June See also Container 5, same heading (Box 33)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1953-1954
    - Correspondence
      - Committee of Social Science Consultants
        - 1955, July-1956, Mar.
        - 1956, Apr.-1957, Jan.
        - 1957, Jan.-Apr.
        - 1957, May-Dec.
        - 1958
        - 1959-1961
      - Miscellaneous, 1950-1954
    - Desegregation experts, 1956
    - Educational standards, guidance, placement, circa 1957
    - "Ending Segregation in Public Education" (Box 34)
      - Correspondence, 1953-1954
      - Drafts, 1951-1953
        - 1 of 2
        - 2 of 2
    - Expenses
      - 1952-1956
      - 1957-1961
    - Memoranda
      - 1951-1953
      - 1956, Jan.-May
      - 1956, Sept.-Dec.
      - 1957
      - 1958-1960
    - Monthly reports
      - 1952-1953
      - 1954-1955
    - Schools (Box 35)
      - Amityville, N.Y.
        - Clippings, 1954
        - Copiague school district, undated
        - Miscellaneous reports, 1953-1956, undated
        - Union Free School District No. 6, 1954
      - Delaware
        - Clippings, 1953-1957
        - Correspondence
          - 1952, July-1953, Feb.
          - 1953, Mar.-Aug.
          - 1954
          - 1955-1960
        - Hockessin community schools, 1953
        - School data
          - Miscellaneous, 1953-1955 See also Oversize
          - Printed material, 1951-1953
      - General correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 36)
      - Illinois
        - Alton
          - Correspondence, 1951-1953
          - Miscellaneous, 1951, undated
          - Press reports and clippings, 1951-1952
        - Massac and Pulaski counties, 1951-1952
        - Printed material and clippings, 1948-1954
        - Reports and correspondence, 1951-1953
      - Social science background reports, 1950-1955
      - Statement concerning New York City school desegregation, 1956-1957
    - "Study of Community Acceptance of Desegregation in Two Selected Areas," for Journal of Negro Education, 1954
  - Smith, Rufus, 1953-1961 (Box 37)
  - Speakers, miscellaneous, 1955-1956
  - Staff meetings and memoranda See also Container 31, Reports
    - 1950-1952
    - 1953-1956
  - Tax status, 1946-1957
  - Taylor, Herman L., 1944, 1950-1953
  - Taylor, William, 1954-1959
  - Turead, A. P., 1948-1953
  - Union negotiations
    - Agreement, 1949
    - Background material, 1946-1947
  - Youth department, 1954
- Subject File, 1929-1968 (Box 38-175)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, notes, legal documents, newspaper clippings, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, person, geographical area, or type of material.
  - Abstracts of litigation, undated (Box 38)
  - Air Force
    - Copeland, Raymond, 1955-1957
    - Davis, Robert A., 1949-1951
    - *Hamilton, J. C., 1950-1954
    - *Huffman, Vivian, 1955
    - General correspondence
      - * 1950-1954, (7 folders)
      - * 1955-1959, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Jenkins, Silas M., 1952-1953
    - *Johnson, Casey, 1954
    - *Johnson, John J., 1954-1956
    - *Lee, Shade M., 1950-1960
    - Press releases and clippings, 1950-1952
    - *Stewart, Harry T., and Gordon M. Rapier, 1955-1956
    - *Summerford, John W., 1955
  - Alabama
    - Eufala, 1955-1957
    - Notes on doing business in, 1956, undated
  - American Bowling Congress, 1949-1950
  - American Jewish Committee, 1952-1961
  - American Jewish Congress
    - 1954-1957
    - 1959-1961
  - American Veterans Committee (Box 40)
    - 1948-1951
    - 1952-1954
  - Arkansas Democratic primary, 1942
  - Armed forces See also Containers 38-39, Air Force; Containers 125-126, Navy; Containers 145-158, Soldier Trouble; and Containers 162-173, Veterans' Complaints
    - Brown, R. Jesse, 1957-1960
    - Camps
      - Camp Rucker, Ala., 1951
      - Ft. Dix, N.J., 1943, 1949-1953
      - General correspondence
        - * 1949-1953, (3 folders)
        - * 1954-1957, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Edward, Lawrence, 1959
    - General files
      - 1949
      - 1950, correspondence
      - 1950, press clippings and printed matter
      - 1950, soldier complaints
      - 1951, correspondence
      - 1951, press clippings and printed matter
      - 1951, soldier complaints
      - * 1952 (Box 42)
      - 1952-1953, correspondence
      - 1952-1953, press clippings and printed matter
      - * 1954, correspondence
      - 1954, press clippings and printed matter
      - * 1955
      - * 1956
      - * 1957
      - * 1958, (3 folders)
      - * 1959-1961, (6 folders) (Box 43)
    - *Hugley, John L., 1958
    - Korean War See also Container 18, Korean trip; Container 99, Korea, defense fund; Containers 152-154, Korea; and Container 225, Korean War and World War II Court Martial Records
      - Correspondence, 1950-1951
      - Court martial cases, 1951
      - Press clippings and printed material, 1950-1951
    - National Guard
      - *Correspondence, 1951
      - Maryland, 1955
    - Regulations (Box 44)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1954
      - Printed material, 1929, 1946-1954
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps, land grant colleges, 1960
    - School integration on military bases, 1952-1956
    - *Volman, Violet, 1952-1954
  - Articles
    - Correspondence, 1954
    - Notes on fourteenth amendment, circa 1950
  - Baker, Josephine, Stork Club incident, New York, N.Y.
    - Clippings, 1951-1952
    - Correspondence, 1951
    - Legal documents, 1951
    - Press releases, 1951-1952
    - Proposed legal action (Box 45)
      - 1951, Oct.-Nov.
      - 1951. Dec.-1952, May
    - Publicity campaign, 1951
  - Baltimore urban redevelopment, 1958
  - Billboards, 1951
  - *Brown, Louis, 1953-1954
  - Casey, Alberta
    - * 1952-1954, (3 folders)
    - * 1955, (2 folders) (Box 46)
  - Civil rights See also Containers 74-81, Discrimination
    - Handbook, 1952
    - Miscellany, 1950-1956, undated
    - Model civil rights bill, 1942, undated
    - New Jersey
      - Amusement parks, 1945, 1948
      - Department of Education, Division Against
        - Discrimination
          - Miscellany, 1951-1952
          - Newsletters, 1951-1955
          - Reports, 1949-1954
    - "Statement on the Denial of Human Rights to... Citizens of Negro Descent... in the United States of America and an Appeal to the United Nations for Redress," W. E. B. DuBois, et al., undated
    - Statutes, undated
    - "Survey of State Legislation in the Field of Civil Rights," Marie-Louise Nickerson, 1944
    - "Testimony of Thurgood Marshall... before a Senate Judiciary Committee on... Civil Rights bills," 1949
  - Collected articles and speeches, 1951-1959 (Box 47)
  - Collected cases
    - Bridges v. United States, 1952 (criminal law, Calif.)
    - Brown v. McKie, 1951 (transportation, N.Y.)
    - Burr v. Sondheim, 1954 (education, Md.)
    - Chissel v. Mayor of Baltimore, 1949 (miscellaneous, Md.)
    - Connecticut v. Bradley, 1949 (criminal law, Conn.)
    - County School Bd. v. Freeman, 1948 (education, Va.)
    - Davis v. Bd. of Educ., 1952 (education, Va.)
    - Dillard v. Chesapeake & Ohio Ry., undated (labor, W.Va.)
    - Emspak v. United States, 1952 (criminal law, D.C.)
    - Everett v. Harron, 1954 (recreation, Pa.)
    - Frankfeld v. United States, 1952 (criminal law)
    - Gaddis Inv. Co. V. Morrison, 1952 (housing, Utah)
    - Gelling v. Texas, 1952 (miscellaneous, Tex.)
    - Glicker v. Michigan Liquor Control Comm'n, 1947 (criminal law, Mich.)
    - Green v. City of Portsmouth, 1951 (recreation, Va.)
    - Hearings and petitions
      - Armed forces, 1957
      - Education, 1948-1959
        - 1 of 2
        - 2 of 2
      - Housing, 1949-1953 (Box 48)
      - Labor, 1950-1956
    - Kovacs v. Cooper, 1949 (miscellaneous, N.J.)
    - Leshin v. Ludwig, 1952 (domestic relations, N.Y.)
    - Maryland v. Williams, 1959-1960 (criminal law, Md.)
    - Matheson v. Wilson, 1952 (education, Ky.)
    - Nash v. Wright, 1948 (transportation, Va.)
    - National Lawyers Guild v. Brownell, 1954 (labor, D.C.)
    - New York v. Bell, 1953 (criminal law, N.Y.)
    - New York v. Johnson, undated (criminal law, N.Y.)
    - New York v. Perez, 1949 (criminal law, N.Y.)
    - New York v. Ruthazer, 1956 (criminal law, N.Y.)
    - New York ex rel. Gadson v. Hoy, 1954 (criminal law, N.Y.)
    - Norris v. Mayor of Baltimore, 1947 (education, Md.) (Box 49)
    - North Carolina v. Hairston, undated (criminal law, N.C.)
    - North Dakota v. Moore, 1959 (criminal law, N.Dak.)
    - Northwest Civic Ass'n v. Sheldon, 1946 (housing, Mich.)
    - Peay v. Cox, 1951 (elections, Miss.)
    - Railway Express Agency v. New York, 1949 (miscellaneous, N.Y.)
    - Regina v. Lusu, 1953 (transportation, South Africa)
    - Sistruck v. Pendleton, undated (housing, Ga.)
    - Smith v. Farm, 1951 (miscellaneous, N.Y.)
    - United States v. 88 Cases Containing 24 6 3/4 Fluid Ounce Bottles, 1951 (miscellaneous, N.J.)
    - Virgin Islands Bar Ass'n v. Dench, 1954 (miscellaneous, V.I.)
    - Walker v. Texas, 1955 (criminal law, Tex.)
    - Westminster School Dist. v. Mendez, undated (education, Calif.)
    - Wilson v. Louisiana, 1950-1951 (criminal law, La.)
    - Wolfe v. North Carolina, 1959 (recreation, N.C.)
    - Youngstown Sheet & Tube Co. v. Sawyer, 1952 (labor, D.C.)
  - Communism, 1949-1954
  - Court appointments, 1953-1954 (Box 50)
  - Crank letters, 1954-1955
  - Crime
    - *Allen, Lawrence, 1953-1954
    - *Anderson, John, 1951
    - Anderson, Lewis Lloyd, 1960-1961
    - *Anthony, George, 1950-1955
    - *Bailey, George, 1953
    - *Bell, Nathan, 1949
    - *Belpre, Guillermo, 1950-1952
    - *Bey, Irving Morris, 1950-1954
    - *Black, James, 1950-1952
    - Braden, Carl, 1954-1955 (Box 51)
    - Brown, Edward, 1953-1955
    - *Brown, Monroe, 1950-1955
    - *Brown, William P., 1948-1952
    - *Burnette, Clarence, 1951-1954
    - *Bryant, David, 1948-1955
    - *Carey, Zack, 1950-1955
    - Chandler, William C., 1952-1954
    - Choate, Dan, 1953
    - Cockfield, Rudolph, 1949-1951
    - *Cook, Cary T., 1949-1956
    - *Cross, Alline, 1959
    - *Crowe, Burton, 1952-1954
    - *Croxton, Robert, 1948-1955
    - *Cummings, John, 1953
    - *Curtis, John A., 1950-1952
    - Daniels, Bennie, and Lloyd Ray, 1949-1953
    - *Dukes, Jesse, 1952-1955, (2 folders) (Box 52)
    - *Dyer, Philip, 1953-1954
    - *Everett, William, 1953-1954
    - *Extradition, 1952-1957 See also Container 83, same heading, (4 folders)
    - *Favors, Henry H., 1955-1958
    - *Griffin, Willie, 1951-1954
    - Groveland, Fla., 1949-1954 (rape case and riots) See also Containers 123-125, Harry T. Moore; Container 127, Florida; and Containers 220-221, Irvin v. Florida
      - Contributions and expenses
        - 1949
        - * 1950-1953
      - Doggett, Rev. Caxton, Florida Citizens for Justice, 1951-1953
      - Fund-raising tours, 1949-1951 (Box 53)
      - Legal defense
        - Alexander, Carol, 1951-1952
        - Bunch, James, 1952-1953
        - Burtoft, Lawrence, 1951-1952
        - Correspondence
          - 1949, 1 of 2
          - 1949, 2 of 2
          - 1950
          - 1951
          - 1952-1954
      - Protests
        - Correspondence, 1951, Nov.
        - Correspondence, 1951, Dec.-1952, Mar.
        - Telegrams, 1951
      - Public relations (Box 54)
        - Mailings, announcements, reports, 1949-1951
        - Pamphlet distribution and correspondence, 1949-1952
      - Roper, Elmo, "A Study of the Attitudes of Florida Citizens on Some Current Issues," 1952
    - *Harrison, Yancey, 1957-1958
    - Harvey, Smith, 1951-1952
    - Henderson, Clarence, 1950-1953
    - *High, Cleophus, 1953-1954
    - *Holman, George, 1949-1954
    - *Holt, Arthur, 1952
    - *Hooper, Henry, 1961-1962
    - Hopkins, Curtis
      - Case records, 1949-1950
      - Correspondence, 1949-1951
    - *Horton, Jack, and Leola Marie Thomason, 1952 (Box 55)
    - *Hudson, James Willy, 1954-1955
    - *Jackson, Alfred, 1951-1952
    - *Keeton, L. C., 1948-1951
    - Ku Klux Klan
      - Fitzgerald, Charles, 1951
      - Miscellany, 1950-1952
    - Love, Betty
      - Case records, 1948-1951
      - *Correspondence, 1949-1951, (2 folders)
    - Mariner, George L., 1951
    - *Marshall, William Authur, 1951-1953, (2 folders)
    - Maxwell, Herman, 1949-1952
    - McCray, John H. (Box 56)
      - Case records, 1950-1951
      - Correspondence, 1950-1953
      - Notes on case reviews, undated
    - *McGregor, Charles, 1949-1955
    - *McWhorter, Jesse, 1958-1962
    - *Mills, Lawrence, 1953-1955
    - Miscellaneous cases (Box 57)
      - *A, 1951-1962, (2 folders)
      - *B, 1950-1962, (6 folders)
      - *C, 1950-1962, (5 folders)
      - *D, 1950-1955, (2 folders) (Box 58)
      - *E, 1951-1959
      - *F, 1951-1962, (4 folders)
      - *G, 1948-1955, (4 folders)
      - *H, 1951-1962, (7 folders) (Box 59)
      - *I, 1953-1955
      - *J
        - * 1949-1955, (3 folders)
        - * 1956-1962, (3 folders) (Box 60)
      - *K, 1951-1955
      - *L, 1951-1959
      - *M, 1951-1959, (4 folders)
      - *N, 1951-1961
      - *O, 1951-1961